xtm-intl.com 2015-12-27

# 

               Website Privacy Policy
Better Translation Technology

   Published by XTM International Ltd.
   © Copyright XTM International Ltd. All rights reserved. No part of this publication may be reproduced
   or transmitted in any form or by any means, including photocopying, without the written permission of
   XTM International Ltd.
   Updated February 2012
                                                       XTM-International Ltd, PO Box 2167, Gerrards Cross, SL9 8XF, UK
                                            Tel.: +44 (0)1753 480479 email: sales@xtm-intl.com http://www.xtm-intl.com
Page 2

        Table of Contents
1.  What information do we collect? .................................................................................................................. 4
2.  Cookies ......................................................................................................................................................... 4
3.  Using your personal information ................................................................................................................... 5
4.  Disclosures .................................................................................................................................................... 5
5.  International data transfers ........................................................................................................................... 6
6.  Security of your personal information ........................................................................................................... 6
7.  Policy amendments ....................................................................................................................................... 6
8.  Your rights ..................................................................................................................................................... 6
9.  Third party websites...................................................................................................................................... 7
10.    Updating information ................................................................................................................................ 7
11.    Contact ...................................................................................................................................................... 7
12.    Data controller .......................................................................................................................................... 7
                                                                                                                                                                 Page 3

                                       PRIVACY POLICY
   We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; this policy sets out how we will
   treat your personal information.
   Our website uses cookies. By using our website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to our use of
   cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.
    1.        What information do we collect?
   We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal information:
   (a) information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website (including your
         IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source,
         length of visit, page views and website navigation;
   (b) information relating to any transactions carried out between you and us on or in relation to this
         website, including information relating to any purchases you make of our goods or services;
   (c)   information that you provide to us for the purpose of registering with us;
   (d) information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our website services, email
         notifications and/or newsletters and;
   (e) any other information that you choose to send to us.
    2.        Cookies
   A cookie consists of information sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser.
   The information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the
   server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser.
   We use both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies on the website. We will use the session
   cookies to: keep track of you whilst you navigate the website; and. We will use the persistent cookies
   to: enable our website to recognise you when you visit.
   Session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser. Persistent cookies
   will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.
   We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of this website. Google Analytics generates statistical
   and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers.
   The information generated relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of the
   website. Google will store this information.              Google's privacy policy is available at:
   http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html.
   Most browsers allow you to reject all cookies, whilst some browsers allow you to reject just third party
   cookies. For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Internet
   Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector. Blocking all cookies
   will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of our website.
Page 4

 3.       Using your personal information
Personal information submitted to us via this website will be used for the purposes specified in this
privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website.
We may use your personal information to:
(a) administer the website;
(b) improve your browsing experience by personalising the website;
(c)  enable your use of the services available on the website;
(d) send to you goods purchased via the website, and supply to you services purchased via the
     website;
(e) send statements and invoices to you, and collect payments from you;
(f)  send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications;
(g) send you email notifications which you have specifically requested;
(h) send to you our newsletter and other marketing communications relating to our business which
     we think may be of interest to you by post or, where you have specifically agreed to this, by email
     or similar technology (you can inform us at any time if you no longer require marketing
     communications);
(i)  provide third parties with statistical information about our users – but this information will not be
     used to identify any individual user;
(j)  deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to the website.
Where you submit personal information for publication on our website, we will publish and otherwise
use that information in accordance with the license you grant to us.
We will not without your express consent provide your personal information to any third parties for the
purpose of direct marketing.
All our website financial transactions are handled through our payment services provider, SagePay.
You can review their privacy policy at www.sagepay.com. We will share information with SagePay only
to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our website and
dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments.
 4.       Disclosures
We may disclose information about you to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or
subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this privacy policy.
In addition, we may disclose your personal information:
(a) to the extent that we are required to do so by law;
(b) in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;
(c)  in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others
     for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);
(d) to the purchaser (or prospective purchaser) of any business or asset which we are (or are
                                                                                                      Page 5

        contemplating) selling; and
   (e) to any person who we reasonably believe may apply to a court or other competent authority for
        disclosure of that personal information where, in our reasonable opinion, such court or authority
        would be reasonably likely to order disclosure of that personal information.
   Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.
    5.       International data transfers
   Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the
   countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this
   privacy policy.
   Information which you provide may be transferred to countries (including the United States) which do
   not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Area.
    6.       Security of your personal information
   We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or
   alteration of your personal information.
   We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password- and firewall-
   protected) servers. All electronic transactions you make to or receive from us will be encrypted using
   SSL technology.
   Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the
   security of data sent over the internet.
   You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will not ask you for
   your password (except when you log in to the website).
    7.       Policy amendments
   We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. You
   should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.
   We may also notify you of changes to our privacy policy by email.
    8.       Your rights
   You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you. Provision of
   such information will be subject to:
   (a) the payment of a fee (currently fixed at £10.00); and
   (b) the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity (for this purpose, we will usually accept a
        photocopy of your passport certified by a solicitor or bank plus an original copy of a utility bill
        showing your current address).
   We may withhold such personal information to the extent permitted by law.
   You may instruct us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes by email at any
   time. In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal
   information for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of the use of
Page 6

your personal information for marketing purposes.
 9.      Third party websites
The website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or
practices of third party websites.
 10.     Updating information
Please let us know if the personal information which we hold about you needs to be corrected or
updated.
 11.     Contact
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal information,
please write to us by email to sales@xtm-intl.com or by post to PO Box 2167, Gerrards Cross, SL9
8FX, United Kingdom.
 12.     Data controller
The data controller responsible in respect of the information collected on this website is Robert
Willans.
Our data protection registration number is Z2981120.
                                                                                             Page 7

                                   XML International Ltd, PO Box 2167, Gerrards Cross, SL9 8XF, UK
Tel.: +44 (0)1753 480467 Fax: +44 (0)1753 480465 email: sales@xtm-intl.com http://www.xtm-intl.com
